Rory Hartong-Redden

July 23, 2024 | Boulder, CO | roryhr@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/rory-hartong-redden | roryhr.com

## Summary

Data Science Manager experienced in leading and growing productive data science teams

## **Tools**

Python, Git, Shell, Terraform, Elixir SQL, Metabase, Postgres, Spark, Hadoop, S3
Docker, AWS, CircleCI, Github CI/CD Jupyter Notebooks, PyCharm, ChatGPT

Python Tools: Scikit-learn, XGBoost, TensorFlow, pandas, Flask, numpy, Matplotlib, pytest, Spark ML

## **Professional Experience**

• SyBridge Technologies (Fast Radius)

Technical Manager and Data Scientist

Boulder, CO Aug 2021–May 2024

- Led the data science team of 3 as we delivered critical features for the IPO
- Ensured revenue-critical API availability by developing high-quality code and comprehensive test suites, enabling \$10M per month in instant quotes
- Utilized Metabase to generate SQL queries for collect training data and monitor accuracy
- Predicted shipping costs using mixed integer programming and the UPS API
- Provided statistical analysis and visualization support for R&D projects involving diverse data types using Jupyter Notebooks with Python
- Worked with cross-functional teams to align on manufacturing process cost models
- Mentored junior data scientist as we expand coverage and improve models to instantly quote parts

• Fast Radius Chicago, IL

Data Scientist Feb 2020-Aug 2021

- Tech stack: Python, SQL, Scikit-learn, Flask, Docker, AWS ECS, Datadog, Metabase
- Deployed a Dockerized machine learning model powering our eCommerce contract manufacturing business, progressing from ad hoc statistical data exploration to production deployment, to instantly generate customer quotes for the FDM 3D printing process

• runtastic Linz, Austria
Data Engineer Oct 2018–Sep 2019

- Tech stack: Python, Spark, Hadoop, Flume, Oozie, Hive, RabbitMQ
- Led the design and deployment of a "People You Might Know" data product using Spark, scikitlearn, SparkML, and Elasticsearch
- Built a data exchange prototype with Apache Kafka and a production system with AWS S3

• Allstate

Research Analyst

Menlo Park, CA

Jul 2016–Sep 2018

- Tech stack: Python, pandas, TensorFlow, Spark, Julia, PostGIS
- Trained machine learning models and analyzed telematics and crash data for risk prediction
- Co-authored a paper on our research "Real-time Prediction of Intermediate-Horizon Automotive Collision" with the Stanford Intelligent Systems Lab

## Education

• University of California, Santa Barbara MS Mechanical Engineering

Santa Barbara, CA Dec 2014

- Tech stack: MATLAB, SolidWorks, LATEX
- Thesis research: Designed and built an experiment to measure Faraday waves using a novel image processing technique for 3D high-speed mm-resolution measurement over a surface area of  $225\,\mathrm{cm}^2$
- University of California, Santa Barbara BS Physics & BS Mechanical Engineering

Santa Barbara, CA June 2010